

SOLUTION ARCHITECT · CLOUD ARCHITECT · DEVOPS · TECH LEAD

725, Sector 14, Gurugram, Haryana - 122002

□ (+91) 9660100100 | ☑ jobs@anandvyas.in | 🏕 anandvyas.in | 🖸 anandvyas | 🛅 anandvyas | 🦠

"Be the change that you want to see in the world."

Summary

Having more than 11+ years of vast professional experience in IT and 3 years AWS experience as an AWS Solution Architect. Working with various technologies like AWS Web Services, Nodejs, Angularjs, PHP, Drupal, Codeigniter, CakePHP, MongoDB, DynamoDB, Redis, Memcache, JSON, API. As a Solution Architect/Technical Architect/Team Lead in various phase of career gained excellent client and team handling ability. Using this skill to communicate directly with the client and perform the best as a team. Also, have involved and contributed a lot in converting the requirements into effective business design. Always been a part of Release Process and Stage Maintenance.

Skills: AWS Cloud Architect, Elastic Beanstalk, VPC, EC2, S3, SNS, SQS, ELB, Auto Scaling, Cloud Front, Docker, Vagrant, Git, Jenkins, Linux, Redis, Javascript, Node.js, Php, Drupal, MySQL, ElasticSearch

Work Experience

Technodrive Software Solutions.

Hyderabad, IN

SOLUTIONS ARCHITECT & TECHNICAL ARCHITECT

Jan 2018 - Currently

- Architect, design and implement solutions with AWS Virtual Private Cloud (VPC), Elasticbeanstalk, RDS, Elastic Compute Cloud (EC2), Elastic Load Balancer (ELB), AutoScalling, RDS, S3, CloudWatch and other AWS products.
- Ensure success in building and migrating applications, software and services on the AWS platform.
- · Participate in deep architectural discussions to ensure solutions are designed for successful deployment in the cloud.
- · Communicate with the stack holders internally and externally at various level to identify existing IT infra and future need.
- Involved in knowledge sharing and technical guidance to the team members.
- Deployment of code and database on staging and production servers.
- Implementing GIT, CI based workflows in our projects.
- Participate in the Sprint planning process.

SOLUTIONS ARCHITECT & TECHNICAL ARCHITECT

· Performing hands on development when needed.

Srijan Technologies.

Delhi, IN June 2015 - JULY 2017

• Architect, design and implement solutions with AWS Virtual Private Cloud (VPC), Elastic Compute Cloud (EC2), Elastic Load Balancer (ELB), AutoScalling, RDS, S3, CloudWatch and other AWS products.

- Ensure success in building and migrating applications, software and services on the AWS platform.
- · Participate in deep architectural discussions to ensure solutions are designed for successful deployment in the cloud.
- Communicate with the stack holders internally and externally at various level to identify existing IT infra and future need.
- Involved in knowledge sharing and technical guidance to the team members.
- Deployment of code and database on staging and production servers.
- Implementing GIT, CI based workflows in our projects.
- Participate in the Sprint planning process.
- · Performing hands on development when needed.

Cyberlinks Technologies TECHNICAL ARCHITECT / TEAM LEAD

Gurugram, IN

June 2014 - June 2015

- Leading Teams of 2 8 people in successfully delivering projects
- Mentoring the team members
- Ensuring the timely and Quality delivery of projects.
- Working closely with the Project Manager / Business Analyst in understanding requirement and breaking them down.
- Participate in the Sprint planning process and provide breakdown and effort of tasks.
- Working closely with a Mobile Team to develop Web Services and APIs
- Hands on development with the team to deliver web projects
- Deployment and maintenance of developed Web applications

Arcgate Technologies

Udaipur, IN

May 2012 - May 2014

ASSOCIATE TECHNICAL ARCHITECT / TEAM LEAD

- Leading Teams of 2 6 people in successfully delivering projects
- Mentoring the team members
- Ensuring the timely and Quality delivery of projects.
- Working closely with the Project Manager / Business Analyst in understanding requirement and breaking them down.
- Participate in the Sprint planning process and provide breakdown and effort of tasks.

Arcgate Technologies Udaipur, IN

Sr. Developer May 2008 - May 2012

- Developed and maintain PHP/MySQL, Cakephp, Drupal, Wordpress, Nodejs and Javascript based applications.
- · Defining best practices for project support and documentation.
- · Handling application development as well as unit, integration and system testing.
- · Identifying technical & functional requirements / pain areas & mapping the same in line with organizational needs.
- Designing & developing database objects like tables, views, and procedures.
- Coding & Review as per Coding guidelines issued by the client.
- Writing APIs which are used by Mobile Apps or any other platform.
- Consuming APIs of various third party services.

Rajasthan Patrika JAIPUR, IN

DEVELOPER Feb 2007 - May 2008

- Deployment and maintenance of Rajasthan Patrika website.
- Deployment and maintenance of news integration support backend tools.
- · Compare with other news sites and new features.

Acro Computing India HYDRABAD, IN

TRAINEE / DEVELOPER Jun 2006 - Sept 2006

• Trained in PHP, MySQL concepts and its working. Also, got training as a System engineer.

Certifications

Oct 2017 AWS Certified Solutions Architect - Associate, Z8KHJR1111441LW8

 ${\tt Sept\,2017\,\,\textbf{AWS\,Certified\,Developer\,-Associate},} \, {\tt FBVPWNDCCME1QF99}$

Sept 2017 AWS Certified SysOps Administrator - Associate, ECPZTLHCKJQ1QMCE

AWS

AWS

AW.S

Education_

Master in Computer Application (M.C.A)

RAJASTHAN UNIVERSITY (A+ BY NAAC, INDIA)

July 2003 - Aug. 2006

Rajasthan, IN